today we're going to make high protein
keto chocolate peanut butter ice cream
pretty straightforward to make let's get
on and do
it yeah I get asked for a lot of high
protein recipes because people generally
go online and they see all these high
protein ninja creamy recipes and they
actually make them and they're solid as
a rock or they go super powdery and
people are starting to turn around to
the fact that you actually just still
need to make good ice cream in an ininja
creamy can't they're getting a bit
pissed off or making crap so here we are
this is just a protein powder I I use
use whatever you got at hand obviously
this is a chocolate recip so it's better
if it's chocolate flavored doesn't have
to be because we're going to add cocoa
but it will increase that chocolate
flavor somewhat so let's just get stuck
in and make it we are going to need 300
G of milk use whole milk if you got it
into that we're going to add 317 G of
whipping cream 33% if you've only got 36
or 35 just use that it's absolutely fine
into that we're going to add 20 G of
cocoa powder use a nice strong cocoa
powder and then we're going to add 90 G
of alos oh my God new tub I changed the
alos that I use based on availability
and the final two ingredients are Gua
gum and protein powder but what we're
going to do is gently Heat this up just
to about 55 to 60° Centigrade because we
need to get that cocoa powder immersed
into the liquid it needs to be
homogenized just going to heat that up
heat it up as fast as you like it
doesn't make any difference here we're
not bringing anywhere near boiling point
so you don't have to worry about that
just so that the cocoa powder dissolves
nicely into your
liquid so we're at that final stage
cocoa powder doesn't truly dissolve so
if you don't all heat up allowing it to
break down you don't get the flavor you
don't get the color you don't get
anything you need to heat it up to do
that so now we're at that stage it just
looks like hot chocolate in here all we
need to do is to weigh out our protein
powder 43 G and then into that we're
going to add 1 G of gag gum we don't
need a lot cuz this has got other stuff
in it and protein
itself will thicken our base without
stabilizer but what it won't do is
maintain that texture and consistency
like a stabilizer does we're just going
to mix that together we're mixing it
together to break up that Gua gum
incorporate it into
here put that into our mixture while
stirring doing it this way avoids any
overhea of protein powder if you
overcook protein powder it becomes
incredibly thick and and gummy so you
don't want to do that so that's why
we're keeping this heat nice and low
we're probably at about 40° Centigrade
now this is the stage if you were going
to make this in ninja creamy you would
pour this into your ninja creamy and let
it freeze but we're not we're going to
turn put this in our muo normal ice
cream machine so let's get that in
container and that's going to go in the
fridge now until it's completely cooled
down something to note if you're going
to make this in a ninja creamy with zero
overrun you're going to have much higher
calories per tub than you would do if
you Churn it in an ice cream machine and
that is purely because the ice cream
machine will add air like all ice cream
machines should do the ninja creamy any
type and the package had no air at all
which means that your calorie density is
quite high in comparison to an ice cream
machine where you can incorporate
anywhere from 10% up to probably 30 or
40% for a home machine great way of
reducing calories get a proper ice cream
machine we're going to let that chill
down and then we'll come back and deal
with our peanut butter if you're using a
standard ice cream machine get that
powered on and get it cooling down for 5
to 10 minutes then we're going to take
our ice cream base out the fridge and
give it a really good stir before we pop
it in our now chilled ice cream machine
whil that's chining we are going to take
our peanut butter and some coconut oil
this is refined so it doesn't taste a
coconut and we're going to put in about
50 to 100 GS of peanut butter and 1
teaspoon of our coconut oil depends how
much adding you want to do then you're
going to gently melt it in a wave until
it's completely liquid and then stir it
together make sure it's completely
homogenized and we're going to start
loading up our ice cream tub and layer
in periodically some of our peanut
butter then just finish loading up your
ice cream tub and you're going to pop it
in the freezer to harden off for about 3
to 4 hours or as long as you can wait
then when it's time to Scoopy Scoopy
just make a nice solid bowl of your
beautiful ice cream and get that in a
bowl of your choice finally what we're
going to do is we're going to drizzle
over the top some of our gently warmed
peanut butter add in and and look at
that glorious perfect texture chocolate
peanut butter high protein ice cream
you'd never know that this is zero sugar
high
protein M really nice it's technically
not zero sugar because the milk and
cream has lactose in it which is sugar
using alios it's super easy to do these
kind of recipes but you must be careful
with the protein not all protein is
created equally some have loads of stuff
in I mean this one this is just one I
drink but just to give you an idea of
the
ingredients protein blend which is weigh
protein concentrate and isolate milk
proteins natural and or artificial
flavors cocoa gag gum zanam gum
digestive enzymes Stevia sucos soy lein
loads of stuff in there so you have to
be careful when you use this because if
you start adding other ingredients that
will thicken your base it will become
too thick and then it will become too
hard because most Pro proteins or
flavored proteins are heavily stabilized
to to act as
preservatives and that's kind of their
purpose their original purpose what
we're left with here is a delicious ice
cream it's high protein ultra low sugar
basically zero sugar we're looking at
15.8% fat 0.3% sugar 6% milk solid is
nonfat that number is semi- adjustable
depending on the protein powder that you
use uh obviously there's milk proteins
in here so depending on what your
contents is will change that number
somewhat it's relevant to the to the
recipe really 38.6% solids 61.5% water
there's 3 G of carbs per 100 G and 6 g
of protein per 100 G even in a cheap
home machine you'll get at least 10%
overrun so your calories comes down
exponentially the further up the overrun
scale you go in my M machine I'll get
about 30% overrun for this ice cream so
it becomes low calorie as well as keto
anyway let me know if you make this one
let me know if you like it I'm going to
do more keto and zero sugar recipes
moving forward I got to get rid of this
so if you want to see how I'm going to
get rid of this head over to my other
channel waca I'll put a link in the
description below and I'm going to get
into shape thanks so much for watching
don't forget to like And subscribe I'll
see you next time
[Music]